Everything we thought we knew about our world is changing at overwhelming speed
我们的世界正在飞速变化
Our planet is becoming hotter, more polluted and a harsher place to live
我们的星球正变得越来越高温，污染越来越严重，越来越不适宜生存
For so long, humans tried to survive in the face of climate change,
很长时间以来，人类努力在气候变化中生存
and now the climate system is speaking back
现在气候开始回敬了
Never before have we had such awareness of what we are doing to the planet,
我们从来没有如此清楚地意识到我们对这个星球的所作所为
but never before have we had so much power to do something about it
但我们从来没有如此强大的能力来做出改变
This unprecedented time in our journey calls for change
在人类的征途中，这个空前的时代需要变革
to find a better way to live in order to save the human race
为了拯救人类，找到更好的生活方式
Extreme E is bringing about equality in motorsport
Extreme E在赛车运动中带来了男女平等竞争的机会
with male and female drivers racing in cutting-edge fully electric offroad SUVs,
男女车手们驾驶着高科技的纯电动越野SUV，
battling wheel-to-wheel in damaged areas of the planet
在地球上被严重破坏的地区轮对轮竞争
highlighting the threats to our environment and promoting electrification
强调自然环境所遭遇的威胁，推广电动化
This is racing for the future of humanity
这是为了人类未来的赛事
This is the Electric Odyssey
这就是Electric Odyssey
The location of the inaugural round of Extreme E takes place deep within the Arabian deserts of SaudI Arabia
Extreme E的揭幕战的比赛地点位于阿拉伯沙漠的深处
In the ancient lands around the city of Alula in the northwest corner of the country
在这个国家西北角的阿鲁拉古城周围的古老土地上
国家
人口
坐标
地形
沙特阿拉伯
地区
This is an area that played a major role in ancient times
这个地区在古时有着很重要的意义
沙漠化
问题
比赛日期
as a stopover on the important trade routes of the incense trade
作为香料贸易之路上重要的一站
With a natural oasis or wadi within its valley,
山谷中有天然的绿洲和溪谷，
the area has welcomed visitors and weary travellers from the surrounding arid regions throughout the ages
古往今来，这一带迎接着来自周边干旱地区的游客和疲劳的旅者
As the site of the ancient kingdoms of Dedan and Lihyan,
作为Dedan和Lihyan古国的所在地，
they controlled the caravan trade routes before being conquered by the Nabataeans
纳巴泰人征服之前，他们控制着这条商队必经的贸易路线
who established Hegra, famed for its spectacular tombs
纳巴泰人建立了以壮丽墓碑闻名的黑格拉城
This largely undiscovered area holds a timeless mystery that has been carried throughout its complex past
这片未被发现的区域藏着着贯穿其复杂历史的永恒之谜
But we're not here just to give you a lesson in ancient history
但我们来到这里不只是为了给你上一堂历史课
Extreme E is a cutting-edge motorsport like you've never seen before
Extreme E是一项你从未见过的顶尖赛车赛事
So let's get you up to speed with how an X-Prix works
那么让我们来了解一下X-Prix分站赛的赛制
An Extreme E race consists of two laps
一场Extreme E比赛包含两圈
The team's female and male drivers complete one each in any order and can use a hyperdrive power boost once on every lap
每队的男女车手以任意顺序各完成一圈，每圈都可以使用一次power boost
Day one is qualifying made up of two sessions
第一天的排位赛分为两节
All nine teams do two laps in both session one and two
每节中九支队伍各做出两圈成绩
The time set from both are then combined to make up the qualifying order,
通过综合成绩排序决定排位赛最终名次
and the first championship points of the weekend to claim
同时将会出现本周末的第一个积分
The top three go straight to the semi-final,
前三名直接进入半决赛，
fourth fifth and sixth go to the crazy race
四、五、六名进入Crazy Race
with the bottom three heading to the Shootout to decide the last three finishing places of the weekend
最后三名进入Shootout来决出本次分站赛的最后三位的次序
Day two starts with the semi-final
第二天是半决赛
With the top two finishers proceeding to the final
前两名直接进入决赛
leaving one spot up for grabs to be claimed by the winner of the crazy race
剩下的一个名额留给Crazy Race的获胜者
The first team to cross the line in the final wins the X-Prix
决赛中最先冲线的队伍赢下本场分站赛冠军
taking 25 precious championship points and the glory
并光荣带回25分年度积分
Points from all five X-Prixs go towards the overall teams and drivers title
五场分站赛的总积分将会决定车队和车手总冠军
who will conquer these environments and be crowned the first Extreme E champion
也将决定谁会征服这些环境，成为第一届Extreme E世界冠军
In the first round of the series, there was much drama in qualifying on day one of the desert X-Prix
在本系列赛的第一轮，沙漠X-Prix分站赛的第一天充满了戏剧性
Lewis Hamilton's X-44 headed out first
Lewis Hamilton的X-44队首先出发
and their driving talent of Sébastien Loeb and Cristina Gutiérrez set a time that looked hard to beat
Sébastien Loeb和Cristina Gutiérrez做出的成绩看起来难以超越
Dakar legend Carlos Sainz and Laia Sanz combined desert experience couldn't grab them the top spot
达喀尔拉力传奇Sainz和Sanz结合了沙漠比赛的经验，但未能获得首位
as ACCIONA Sainz came close
ACCIONA队紧随其后位居第二
Andretti United looked super fast on their first lap
Andretti United队在第一圈由2019年世界拉力赛冠军Timmy Hansen驾驶
with 2019 world rallycross champ Timmy Hansen behind the wheel
看起来极具竞争力
Just before he handed over the car to his teammate Catie Munnings,
但就在他把车交付给队友Catie Munnings之前
he picked up a rear tyre puncture
他遇到了后胎缓慢爆胎
In the face of adversity, Munnings brought the car home on three wheels,
面对困难，Munnings成功带回这台“三轮车”
which slotted them into a provisional third place
让他们暂列第三
A flat out and fearless lap from RXR driver Molly Taylor meant when she handed over to Johan Christopherson,
Molly Taylor的一圈飞快，在她把车交给Johan Christopherson时
there was a matter of seconds between them and leaders X-44
他们与榜首的X-44仅有几秒只差
A near-perfect lap saw them set the fastest time overall,
紧接着，近乎完美的一圈让他们攀升至第一名
but a penalty for speeding in the switch zone where the driver swap takes place
但是在车手交接的“换人区”，他们因超速而被罚时
saw them tumble down the qualifying order
导致他们从排位赛榜首跌落
Despite this they still managed to finish in the top three
尽管如此，他们仍成功进入前三
and secure a spot in the semi-final alongside ACCIONA Sainz and qualifying winners X-44
并与ACCIONA和杆位X-44一同进入半决赛
As the dust settled and the sun rose over the desert for day two,
尘埃落地，旭日东升
it was finally time for the first wheel-to-wheel racing action to take place
终于来到了第二天的首场轮对轮竞争的时候了
as the top three qualifiers lined up for the semi-final
前三名依次列开准备进行半决赛
Here is your starting list
这是发车位置
So from P3 it's Christopherson and Taylor
第三位是Christopherson和Taylor
from P2 Carlos Sainz and Laia Sanz
第二位Carlos Sainz和Laia Sanz
and from P1 on the poll if you like Sébastien Loeb Cristina Gutiérrez
杆位起步的是Sébastien Loeb和Cristina Gutiérrez
Green light
绿灯亮起
Either side of the grid
每个发车位上
loads of wheel spin from everywhere
大量的磨胎
Christopherson looks to have got the best traction on the outside line
Christopherson在外道抓地力似乎不错
Laia going to try and squeeze across
Laia尝试靠过来
Oh Loeb's getting the squeeze into Carlos Sainz
Loeb也在挤Carlos Sainz
Almost contact between them already
他们之间已经几乎碰到了
Sainz has managed to
Sainz成功冲到前面
Loeb drop behind him Christopherson...
Loeb掉到后面
Side by side now
三台车并驾齐驱
Sainz has pushed him out wide they're running across dirt
Sainz把他推出去，他们处在非赛车线上
Carlos Sainz with the whole shot the driver who hasn't got any racing experience he's in the lead here
没有任何轮对轮比赛经验的Carlos Sainz处于领先位置
Watch now Sainz is blocking off on the inside
小心，Sainz在尝试封内线
Loeb's got him
Loeb超过他了
X-44 with a whole shot
X-44抓住机会
in the background Johan has got extra exit speed with that line through
在后面Johan出弯速度更快
Somehow they've managed to get through
他们都安全通过了一号弯
and it's the Rosberg car that leads
现在是Rosberg的车领先
look at Christopherson,
看看Christopherson
he's broken away because of this dust
一骑绝尘
Look, completely blind
后面的车因为尘土什么都看不见
and the biggest challenge here
这里最大的挑战是
you don't know where those rocks are
你不知道那些石头在哪
you don't know where these hazards that can trick the drivers up
你不知道那些危险点都在哪
as we saw in qualifying are
不会像排位赛看的那么清楚
so this is the big drop that they have to negotiate
这是他们要面临的巨大下坡
100 meter drop at 45 degree angle
100米落差，45度倾角
You can see the air that they got there for Christopherson
你能明显看到Christopherson的滞空
now it's the turn of Loeb
现在轮到Loeb
Oh a lovely jump
哦，优美的飞跃
there's a long way back route
下半程的赛道还很长
ACCIONA Sainz are a long way back
ACCIONA还在很后面
I think Carlos has backed out of it a little bit just to get some visibility and get a clean run through
我觉得Carlos主动落后了一些就为了能看清楚一点跑的干净一些
He's nearly 20 seconds now behind Christopherson
他落后Christopherson将近20秒
Into the switch zone then
进入换人区
Molly Taylor, we can see running across to jump in and swap out for Christopherson, they've got..
我们可以看到Molly Taylor跑过去跳进车换下Christopherson
Look at the advantage they've got
看他们这优势
Sainz is just coming in
Sainz这才刚进站
Molly Taylor's doing a great job she's extending the lead here over Gutiérrez
Molly Taylor做得很好，她在扩大与Gutiérrez之间的领先优势
Nico Rosberg he'll be delighted with how this opening race has gone
揭幕战这样的局势，Rosberg应该会很高兴
Brilliant drive by Johan Christopherson off the start
Johan Christopherson漂亮的开场
but it's Molly Taylor who brings the car home
但最终是Molly Taylor成功带回
to win the first ever semi-final
拿下第一场半决赛
They book a space in the final
他们在决赛中预定下一个位置
That perfectly executed cutback by Christopherson at turn three left RXR's rivals in the dust
Christopherson在三号弯完美的交叉线超车让RXR的竞争者们消失在尘埃中
and with the pressure on in lap two Molly Taylor remain composed and in control
在第二圈的压力下Molly Taylor保持镇定
to bring the car home and secure their place in the final
成功把车带回确保了他们在决赛中的位置
X-44 will join them after making it through the dust in one piece and crossing the line in second
X-44安全穿过尘埃，第二名冲线
meaning ACCIONA Sainz's weekend ends at the semis
ACCIONA的周末止步于半决赛
RXR have looked fast so far this weekend
RXR队本周末看起来速度很快
But for team boss Nico having an Extreme E team is about more than just racing
但是对于车队老板Rosberg来说，成立一支Extreme E车队不仅是为了赛车
We want to fight for the wins
我们希望获胜
I mean that's what we're here for
这是我们来比赛的主要原因
and I think we're on for that
我觉得我们现在还是很有实力的
Other teams that are seemingly most competitive at the moment is X-44
其他队伍里看起来最有竞争力的是X-44
So that's kind of the people to beat at the moment
所以他们是目前我们要击败的目标
Point though, of taking part in this championship is that
重点是，我们参与到这项赛事中
just as important as fighting for wins
和争冠同等重要的
is the impact that we're going to have
是我们所带来的影响
The social cause is the foundation of the championship and this is why I'm here
社会事业是这项赛事的基础，这是我参加的原因
because that's my passion
因为这是我的激情所在
And I want to do everything in my power as well
我也想尽我所能
to support that and to accelerate climate action around the world
支持并加快世界各地的气候拯救行动
Because it's time now
因为也确实是时候了
I mean we're really running late
其实可能已经有点晚了
and this is what I love about Extreme E
这也是我喜欢Extreme E的一点
it's really the crossover between sustainability and awesome racing
这是可持续发展和精彩比赛的结合
Climate change certainly is a global problem
气候变化是全球性的问题
and it's pretty clear that if we let the planet warm to two degrees and beyond
如果我们让地球变暖两度或更高
that the change is going to be drastic
这种变化显然是很可怕的
It's not really what we want to do
我们并不希望如此
It's a war on all of us and we should be united in it
这是全人类面临的挑战，我们要团结起来
The moment we're not really we're divided into camps into nationalities with vested interests
这个时刻我们不能在分帮结派，不应该再纠结国籍或者个体利益
Sea level doesn't need a visa
海平面不需要签证
Carbon dioxide crosses political borders day and night
二氧化碳每天都随意跨越国界
It's a truly global problem
这真的是全球性问题
So the urgency really is on to stop making the problem worse
所以当务之急是不要让问题继续恶化
Burning of fossil fuels really cuts across so much of what we do
燃烧化石燃料是主要问题
All our power pretty much comes from fossil fuels that transport is responsible for about 30% of the of the emissions
我们大部分能量来源是化石燃料，而交通运输业占了大约30%的排放
The way that we treat forests and cut them down and
我们大量的伐木
they are machines really to take carbon out of the atmosphere
而它们其实是大气的固碳机
All of that is daft behavior
这些都不是什么明智之举
What we need to do now is apply our minds to solutions
我们现在需要运用我们的思想来解决问题
I think Extreme E is leading the way and showing us what we could do
我认为Extreme E正在引领我们，向我们展示我们可以做出哪些改变
One of the ways Extreme E is trying to help
Extreme E帮助保护环境的一种方式
is by leaving a positive legacy behind in each of the locations it visits
是在每个比赛地点留下有积极影响的环保项目
In Saudi Arabia one of the projects it's supporting is the planting of trees,
在沙特阿拉伯的项目是植树造林
near the UNECO world heritage site of Hegra
在联合国教科文组织世界遗址Hegra附近植树
as a means to help combat desertification in the region
作为帮助该地区防治荒漠化的一种方式
We were happy to teach them how to take the seedlings how to put it there
我们很高兴能教他们如何栽苗
just give them like more feeling of fluffing the nature
主要是让他们感受帮助大自然
and they'll want to do more because they saw the result they saw their trees
他们会喜欢上这种感觉，因为他们会看到他们曾经种的树成长起来
The projects is about to restore the cultural landscape here in Hegra
这个项目的目的是恢复Hegra地区的文化景观
and to replant the plants here
另外恢复植被
The project started with 10,000 seedlings and we're aiming to 3,000,000 seedlings
项目初始籽苗数是一万，我们的目标是三百万
We are trying to replant this native species like this small seedling
我们尝试恢复本地植被种类，就像这种小籽苗
and future will became like a big like three four five meters trees
未来会长成三五米的大树
They will filtration the air
它们可以净化空气
They will stop desertification
它们可以阻止沙漠化
It's full circle like you can imagine the plants like air-conditioner
这是个完整的生态圈，你可以把植被想象成空调
Then animals can come,
然后动物会来
Gazelle and all these animals cannot be here without vegetation
羚羊和所有这些动物脱离了植被就无法生存
These plants doesn't need a lot of water
这些植物不需要大量的水
They need a little, like, amount of water that comes from rain
它们只需要少量雨水
The roots will go down and find the water and they will be totally fine,
然后它们的根会往下扎，找到水分，然后它们就可以活住了
like the other trees here
就像这里其它的树一样
I think from the environment perspective
从环境角度来看
We can have like bring alive here
我们可以恢复这里的生机
because this is not just UNESCO site
因为这里不仅是联合国教科文组织指定的遗址
It's like a reserve it's like a life area
这里也是生态保护区
With the global adventure of Extreme E having finally begun in Saudi Arabia
Extreme E的全球旅程从沙特阿拉伯开始
The seemingly impossible dream of racing in the most remote corners of the world was now a reality
在世界上最偏远的角落赛车这个看似不可能的梦想现在变成了现实
This leap into the unknown would be a brave step for 2009 F1 world champion Jenson Button
对2009年F1世界冠军Jenson Button来说，这是迈入未知领域勇敢的一步
as he would be taking on the challenge as both driver and team boss of JBXE
他将以JBXE车手和车队老板的双重身份接受挑战
But he was interested in the series from the outset
但他从一开始就对这个系列赛充满兴趣
You know I thought it sounded fantastic,
我觉得这听起来很棒
but uh you know a lot of fantastic things don't come to fruition,
但是很多听起来很美好的事最终都不能实现
so you know it's something that's very difficult
所以其实这是很困难的
because you're traveling the world
因为你要周游全世界
going to places that no one's really set foot on
去到那些无人涉足的地方
um so yeah
所以呢
There's a lot to come together for it to actually happen
需要很多努力才能真正落实
You know fair play to Alejandro and the whole team,
这要感谢Alejandro和他的团队
you know to see this live and to see what he's achieved so far
我们才能最终看到这场赛事，这是他的成就
It's very special and we can achieve great things with racing
我们可以通过赛车的形式做更伟大的事，这种感觉很特别
but also bringing awareness to the areas that have been so effective with climate change
但同时还要让大家认识到气候变暖的问题
Jenson had chosen Mikaela Åhlin-Kottulinsky as his teammate
Jenson选择了Mikaela Åhlin-Kottulinsky作为他的队友
who had been helping develop the car since the beginning
她也从一开始帮助开发车辆
To be here from the start when there was no Jenson Button involved or Nico Rosberg or Lewis Hamilton
最开始来到这项赛事，当时还没有Button、Rosberg、Hamilton这些人参与
and everybody was just asking me:
所有人都在问我：
Do you really think this series is going to happen?
你觉得这个系列赛真的能成吗？
And to be here now with all these names in the series
而现在在这里看到这些大名
also especially being in JBXE
尤其是身处JBXE车队
It's just amazing and it makes me feel proud, to be honest,
从一开始规模没有这么大的时候就能参与其中，
to have been a part from the start when it was it wasn't this big
说实话，感觉很自豪很激动
and here we are now
而现在发展到了这个阶段
We're gonna have very different terrains all around the world and the five races
五场比赛我们将会在世界各地面临完全不同的五种地形
which is what makes it so exciting
这是这项赛事令人兴奋的地方
I don't think one person has an advantage over others
我觉得现在没有谁有明显优势
I've done three races off-road
我开过三场越野赛
and I've driven a rally car to practice you know sliding a car and
我开过拉力车练习拉力那种带一点漂移的跑法
so I kind of understand it but this thing is very different
所以我多少了解一些，但这又是完全不同的感觉
The first time that I went up to full power in Wales it was yeah proper exciting
第一次在威尔士全力推这辆车的时候绝对很刺激
I mean I went slower around the lap that we had
我们跑的那圈不是很快
because you're just there to control the whole time trying to control it so
因为你要全程尝试控制好车辆
there's definitely going to be a bit of air
肯定会有一些跳跃滞空
but I mean you've got to really think on your feet which is which I think is awesome
你要想清楚脚下的节奏，这一点我觉得很棒
I think that's great for all of us
我觉得我们所有人都有不少收获
It's not from experience, it's not muscle memory
没有先前的经验作参考，不能靠肌肉记忆
So I'm really looking forward to challenging myself and the car around these different terrains
所以我很期待在不同的地形中挑战自己挑战这台车
I think it's going to be so important to be able to work together
我认为合作是相当重要的
to give each other information about the practice lap what were your thoughts
每一个练习圈下来都要相互交流信息和想法
to try to find the car that suits both of the drivers
尝试把车调到两个人都适合的状态
so I think the teamwork is going to be so important
所以我认为团队合作会非常重要
and that's why I was also happy at the testing in Wales because
我也很高兴能在威尔士试车
I mean you were really helpful
毕竟你帮了我不少忙
Thank you
谢谢
But I think we understand the car reasonably well
我认为我们对车的理解还算不错
We have the same sort of feeling of what we'd want from a car which is great
我们对调车的方向感觉大致相同
Never going to be identical but the thing is we get such limited testing with the car anyway
当然不可能完全一样，不过在这么短的试车时间里
so we can at least put it into a place where we both feel comfortable with it
我们至少把车开发到了我们两人开起来都比较舒服的状态
People are going to have incidents
肯定会有事故
You know these these cars are very powerful they're not so easy to drive
这些车动力十足，不是那么好驾驭
it's a different condition to what most people have tested it in
真实情况和大多数人测试的情况不同
and the course is pretty insane, so I think you're going to have a lot of drivers with big smiles on their face
赛道很夸张，所以我觉得你会看到许多车手脸上大大的笑容
We're all on the same page
我们想的都一样
We want to go racing we want to have fun racing we want to win
我们都想去比赛，我们都想开心地比赛，我们都想赢
but in terms of what it means you know sustainability
但是从可持续发展的角度来说
I think it's great you know I think
我觉得这很棒
We have a voice as drivers especially you know the the Nico Rosbergs of this world and the Lewis Hamiltons and myself
作为车手我们可以发声呼吁，尤其是像Rosberg、Hamilton和我
being an F1 world champion
这些F1世界冠军
and people do stand up and listen which is great
人们会认真倾听我们的声音
and we're pushing this as hard as we possibly can to help the issues that are out there with climate change
而我们也会尽我们所能帮助解决全球气候变暖的问题
Extreme E's revolutionary electric SUV, the Odyssey 21
Extreme E的革命性电动SUV——Odyssey 21
极速
加速
重量
is designed to take on perhaps the toughest challenge in motorsport
被设计用于接受赛车运动中最艰难的挑战
The car's battery stores 40 kW•h of usable energy
这辆车的电池储存着40千瓦时的可用能量
The equivalent of a 550 horsepower combustion engine
电机相当于550匹马力的内燃机
电池
储能
高性能
锂离子
40千瓦时
可用能量
The equivalent of a 550 horsepower combustion engine
电机相当于550匹马力的内燃机
with dual motors makes it capable of creating 1,000 N•m of torque
双电机可以提供1000牛米的扭矩
单电机最大功率
扭矩平衡  可调
底盘材料  铌
The chassis, crash structure and roll cage are manufactured using a Niobium reinforced steel alloy tubular frame
底盘、缓冲装置和防滚架均采用                生产的铌增强合金管架制造
This provides the strength needed to keep drivers safe in case of an accident
这样的强度在事故中可以保证车手的安全
This is going to be close all to play
成绩将会很接近
Ohh! Side ways went into a roll!
哦！车身横过来翻了！
Massive off!
严重失误
That's huge!
重大事故
We are super happy that Claudia is in one piece
我们很高兴看到Claudia安然无恙
and it also shows that the car is safe when you have an accident like that
同时也说明在你遇到这样的事故时，车是很安全的
The bodywork is made from a high-performance natural flax fibre composite
车身是由高强度天然亚麻纤维复合材料制成
which is not only a renewable CO₂ neutral material
这不仅是可重复利用的二氧化碳中性材料
but also lightweight and durable
同时也很轻便结实
Large ventilated disc brakes are responsible for slowing and stopping the car
巨大的刹车片负责车辆减速
制动器
直径355毫米
铁合金
通风式制动盘
While the huge dampers of the suspension system are designed to absorb the impacts of the varied environments that it will race upon
而悬挂系统的巨大减震被设计用来吸收不同比赛路面带来的冲击
悬挂系统
行程335毫米
and can be adjusted to suit conditions
并且可以根据实际情况进行调整
Every time you go out there and the ruts are getting rougher and the jumps you know are getting harsher as the days go on
一天下来，每次出去赛道都会越来越粗糙，跳坡越来越陡
but having the cars held up really well so we're really happy
但是车都应对自如，所以我们很高兴
The all-purpose multi-versatile tyres designed by Continental
由                  生产的多功能通用轮胎
直径
宽度
胎纹深度
will provide unrivaled grip on ice, sand, rock and mud
可以在冰面、散沙、石头和泥地中提供强大的抓地力
They are the most durable tyres ever made in their class
是同类产品中最耐久的轮胎
and will provide racing performance on challenging terrains
同时可以在不同的地形上提供卓越的性能
Cars performed really well in this environment
车在这种环境下表现很好
I've gone over some bigger rocks than I thought was ever possible
我驶过了一些很大的石头
The Odyssey 21 is built to deliver unparalleled performance as sustainably as possible in the most extreme environments
Odyssey 21是为了在极端环境中提供尽可能持续稳定的高性能
The location of the desert X-Prix and Alula certainly is an extreme environment
X-Prix沙漠分站赛的比赛地点阿鲁拉绝对称得上是一个极端环境
situated deep within the vast Arabian desert
其位于广袤的阿拉伯沙漠的深处
But it has been home to human civilization for thousands of years
但数千年来，这里一直是人类文明的家园
After the Dedanite settled here around the 8th century BC
最早是Dedanite公元前八世纪在此安居
the next major civilization was the Nabataeans
然后是纳巴泰人建立的文明
who established Hegra, the second biggest city of the kingdom after Petra in what is now known as Jordan,
他们建立了黑格拉，继佩特拉城之后的第二大古城，也就是现在的约旦境内
an important stop on the Incense Road
这是香料之路上重要的一站
the majority of what is left is a collection of tombs carved into the natural sandstone
现在剩下的大部分是被天然风化的墓碑
and is now a UNESCO world heritage site
现已被联合国教科文组织列为世界文化遗产
Now this is a place which is known as a Hegra
这个地区被称为黑格拉
but locally as known as Madâin Sâlih
但当地人称之为Madâin Sâlih
The Nabataeans when they conquer here exactly and one early one BC they found 150 tombs plus the 130 water wells in this area underground
纳巴泰人在公元前一世纪时征服这里，发现了150座墓碑和130口水井
During the Nabataeans when they conquer this area
在纳巴泰人统治时期
they building a huge water management
他们建立了一个庞大的水资源管理系统
and they use it as a way to store the rain water
作为一种储存雨水的方法
and then they store it in water container
他们将水存放在容器中
The water is the only reason the existing industrialization
水是工业存在的唯一原因
because without water this civilization cannot survive the hot desert environment in today
因为如果没有水，人类文明无法在这样高温的沙漠环境下存在
there's a line over there they carve it all the way
那里有一条线，是他们一路刻出来的
so they know the direction of the water
这样他们能知道水的流向
When the rain that times hits this area and then they carve it through the here
雨水落到这片区域会冲刷这里
and then all the way inside this water container
然后一路流进这个水容器中
so we are right now in this the biggest tomb in this area
我们现在在这片区域中最大的墓碑前
called the Lihyan Son of Kuza
叫做库扎之子利哈亚尼古墓
This is the most iconic tombs in the last cave in the Hegra.
这是这片区域最标志性的墓碑
This guy he was actually a general, Nabataean general, that time
这个人在当时是一位纳巴泰将军，
and some people say he was a king at that time
有些人说他是当时的国王
The Nabataeans and some people they're just moving
纳巴泰人和其他一些人民突然就迁移了
because the trade road of the Incense Road has suddenly uh no longer able to trade
因为香料之路突然不能继续贸易
The people or that time they just vanish they just go somewhere else and they became a history
当时这里的人民就这么消失了，他们就迁移到其他地区，成为了历史
As part of Extreme E's scientific committee,
作为Extreme E的科学委员会的一员
professor Carlos Duarte has been pivotal in advising on the turtle conservation legacy project
Carlos Duarte教授是海龟保护项目的主要提议人
that the series will leave behind in Saudi Arabia
这是这项赛事要留在沙特阿拉伯的项目
But along with endangered turtle species,
但是除了濒危的海龟种群
the Red Sea has many important environmental stories to tell
红海还有许许多多的生态环境故事
Not least its incredible coral reefs,
尤其是漂亮的珊瑚礁
an ecosystem that has suffered globally at the hands of climate change
一种正在受全球气候变暖影响的生态系统
Recently climate change has emerged as the most serious threat to coral reefs
最近，气候变化已成为珊瑚礁面临的最严重威胁
where we are already seeing major mortality of corals around the ocean due to extreme temperatures
我们已经看到各地海洋中的珊瑚因为极端温度而大量死亡
Professor Duarte is part of the incredible work being done by the Red Sea research center
Duarte教授是红海研究中心的一员
based at the King Abdullah University for Science and Technology,
其位于阿卜杜拉国王科技大学中
along with professor Manuel Aranda, a specialist in coral genetics
他与珊瑚专家Manuel Aranda教授共事
The Red Sea is one of the hottest oceans on the planet yet coral thrives here
红海是地球上最热的海洋之一，而珊瑚生活在这里
So people might think that we could just take the coral from the Red Sea
所以有些人可能认为我们可以从红海取一部分珊瑚
and put them elsewhere and let them go there
然后放到其他地区任其生长
The problem is they have adapted to this specific environment
但问题是，它们已经适应了这种特定环境
If we bring them to the great barrier reef, they might not like the salinity
如果我们把它们放到大堡礁周围，它们可能不喜欢那里的盐度
because the Red Sea is much more saline
因为红海的盐含量更高
they might not like the nutrient levels
它们可能不喜欢那里的的营养水平
because the Red Sea is much nutrient productive
因为红海里养分更丰富
So simply taking them from one point and putting it somewhere else works only in very very rare cases
所以简单地把它们从一处转移到另一处，大部分情况下无法成功
The problem is that in the Red Sea they have thousands of years to adapt over time
它们花了几千年适应了红海环境
but climate change is happening at an unprecedented rate
但气候变化速度前所未有的快
It's so fast that we're scared that corals might not be able to keep pace with increasing temperatures
我们害怕珊瑚的进化可能跟不上温度上升的速度
We're trying to find out
我们正在尝试
can we identify individual colonies that are more resilient to climate change
能不能找出某种特定的更适应气候变化的个体群落
and then cross them with colonies from out there in the ocean
然后把他们与海洋中的其它群落杂交
to slowly increase resilience of the coral population
来慢慢增强珊瑚的适应能力
We've done experiment with a smaller number of coral species that showed that it is indeed possible
我们通过对一小部分珊瑚的实验发现，这是可行的
We can take a colony from a very warm location that is naturally adapted to a high temperature
我们可以把从温暖地区去一些自然适应高温的
and cross it with a colony from a cold location
然后与寒冷地区的珊瑚杂交
and still produce offspring that is very very resilient to high temperatures
而还能产生适应高温的珊瑚
This basically tells us that we can't speed up the evolutionary process
这告诉我们，虽然我们不能加速进化过程
The most important thing is that we need to start tackling the real problem
最重要的是我们需要着手解决真正的问题
which is reducing carbon footprints
那就是减少碳足迹（碳排放量）
starting to work on technologies that might allow us to actively remove CO₂ from the atmosphere
着手研究一些能主动从大气中减少二氧化碳的科技
and basically make sure that we don't get too close to that tipping point
然后尽量保证我们尽量不要太靠近失衡点
With two out of the three places in the Deserte X-Prix final already filled by RXR and X-44
X-Prix沙漠分站赛决赛的三个位置中，两个位置已经被RXR和X-44占领
it was time for the Crazy Race to decide who would claim the last spot
现在轮到Crazy Race来决出谁获得这最后一个位置
Andretti United's Timmy Hansen lined up alongside Hispano Suiza Xite Energy driver Oliver Bennett
Andretti United队的Hansen身旁是Xite Energy Racing的车手Bennett
and 2009 F1 champion Jenson Button was on the outside grid position
和处在外侧发车格的2009年F1世界冠军Jenson Button
And we are off
比赛开始
So all three cars trying to find some traction
三台车都努力寻找抓地力
The sand plumes coming up behind them
他们身后一阵沙尘
It looks like Hanson's got the lead straight out the block
看起来是Hanson出发车区后率先取得领先位置
Jenson Button coming through on the left
Jenson Button偏向左侧
and then last is the Hispano Suiza
然后是Xite Energy Racing队
but a really nice start there for Timmy Hansen all those years of experience
Timmy Hansen凭借多年的经验跑出的漂亮的起步
really gaining for him and he's managed to get a clear lead
让他取得明显的领先
That's what he needed
这正是他所需要的
but to the left and right both the Button and Bennett have taken their lines
但是左右两侧Button和Bennett都占据了线路
They've tried to find some clear spaces
他们尝试找到一个干净的位置
They head down to the first gate
他们驶向第一个检查点
Hansen swinging the back end round and he goes through first
Hansen第一个过检查点，狠狠甩了一下车尾
It looks like Button's lost a bit of momentum here
看起来Button丢失了一些速度
Timmy Hansen though broken away
Timmy Hansen已经脱离车阵了
He's done exactly what he and Andretti would have wanted to do
他做到了他自己和队伍所期望的状态
At the switch Timmy handed the car over to Catie Munnings with a big lead over Hispano Suiza Xite and JBXE
在换人区Timmy把车交给Munnings时与另外两队之间有巨大的领先优势
After suffering a puncture at this point the previous day
前一天的这个时候他们遭遇了爆胎
A place in the final had seemed unreachable
决赛的位置看似遥不可及
If you think about yesterday their first run yesterday
如果你想想昨天他们的第一个飞驰圈圈
they're thinking we're not gonna make the final we're done we've had a puncture this is this is game over
他们想着我们决赛无望了，遭遇了爆胎这周末就结束了
They ended up making it through to the Crazy Race and at the minute they're in the box seat to make it to the final
结果他们赢下了Crazy Race，成功晋级决赛
What a great turnaround for them
多么不可思议的转折啊
Only one car going through for the Crazy Race and it's going to be the Andretti United machine Catie at the wheel now
只有一辆车可以晋级，而这辆车将是Andretti United的车，现在是Catie驾驶
Timmy Hansen having given her a great lead on the way in
Timmy进站的时候给了她巨大的领先优势
and they are in the final
而他们成功晋级决赛
Fantastic performance
出色的表现
A perfect launch of the start and two flawless laps secured Andretti United's place in the final
完美的起步和完美的两圈确保了Andretti United的决赛位置
with Hispano Suiza excite energy coming in second and JBXE rounding out the order
Xite Energy Racing第二名，JBXE最后冲线
Timmy really sent it off the start line
Timmy在起点冲的很猛
and he just did an amazing job in taking the lead there and then managing that
他漂亮地取得了领先，然后一切都在掌握之中
and obviously when he came in
显然当他进站的时候
I've got one job and that's to keep it on the road
我只要做好一件事，把车稳在路上
I'm really happy to be here
我很高兴来到这里
um let's start this week you know with the first qualifying we had a puncture
这周末一开始我们遇到了爆胎
so now to be in the final
而现在我们晋级决赛
It just says that anything can happen
真的是一切都有可能发生
and you have to really make sure that you're keeping check of every second for every round
你需要保证每一轮每一刻都检查好车辆
With the last spot in the final secured,
最后一个决赛位置敲定
the lineup was ready and the stage was set
阵容准备好了，舞台布置好了
Next time on Electric Odyssey
下一期的Electric Odyssey中
We'll check out the jaw-dropping action of the Shootout race
我们将一览令人瞠目结舌的Shootout赛
He's in the dust now looking for a way through
他在尘土中寻找线路超越
no lifting
没有松油门
and of course we will see who claimed the Desert X-Prix crown
当然我们也会看到谁摘得了X-Prix沙漠分站赛桂冠
Here we go
比赛开始了
Green light on the outside.
两侧绿灯亮起
字幕：Lee-7723